<?xml version='1.0' encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.0/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
<bookinfo>
	<title>SynCE Documentation</title>

	<author>
		<firstname>SynCE</firstname><surname>Development Team</surname>
		<affiliation>
		<address>
			<email>synce-devel@lists.sourceforge.net</email>
		</address>
		</affiliation>
	</author>

	<pubdate>2007-05-07</pubdate>

	<revhistory>
		<revision>
			<revnumber>0.1</revnumber>
			<date>2007-05-07</date>
			<authorinitials>Jonny Lamb</authorinitials>
			<revremark>First draft</revremark>
		</revision>
	</revhistory>

	<abstract>
		<para>This is the user manual for the SynCE project. The purpose of the SynCE project is to provide a means of communication with a Windows Mobile, or Windows CE, device from a computer running Linux, FreeBSD or a similar operating system.</para>
	</abstract>
</bookinfo>

<chapter id="introduction">
	<title>Introduction</title>

	<para>This is section 1 with a nice little paragraph.</para>

	<sect1 id="history">
		<title>SynCE History</title>

		<para>The SynCE project was started by Ludovic Lange. The SourceForge project pages were established at this time and the first version of the RAPI library appeared in the CVS. David Eriksson joined the project in July 2001 and became a project manager in October. In the following few months the basic functions of the library (initialization and file handling) took shape and a few simple tools appeared.</para>

		<para>Ganesh Varadarajan started to contribute USB code about March 2002.</para>

		<para>Progress was fairly slow until David Eriksson reorganized the library code into separate libraries with cleaner interfaces in July 2002. This was followed by new modules for connecting to the PDA (synce-serial) and a replacement for the ayncd program (dccm). In October 2002 the database write functions were made to work and September 2002 the registry functions made their first appearance.</para>

		<para>In November 2002 David released the first packaged distribution of the SynCE code and established the user mailing list. In December 2002 Richard Taylor released the first version of the Python wrappers for librapi2.</para>

		<para>TODO- I was not around here, and do not know what happened in this section!</para>

		<para>When Windows Mobile version 5 was released, SynCE was reported not to work at all. Upon reverse engineering the protocols used for synchronisation and connection, it was discovered that devices now used RNDIS instead of serial, and the protocol used for syncing PIM items (formerly RRAC) had been changed to use AirSync, and XML-based protocol. This required serious reverse-engineering.</para>

		<para>Luckily, this is when Ole André Vadla Ravnås stepped in. He had been around contributing code, and updating other libraries, but his love was reverse engineering.</para>

		<para>TODO- finish this section, preferably before my memory fails.</para>
	</sect1>

</chapter>

<chapter id="synce_wm5">
	<title>SynCE with Windows Mobile 2005</title>

	<para>TODO- introduction</para>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm5_install">
		<title>Installation</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm5_configuration">
		<title>Configuration</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm5_usage">
		<title>Usage</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm5_troubleshooting">
		<title>Troubleshooting</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

</chapter>

<chapter id="synce_wm2003">
	<title>SynCE with Windows Mobile 2003 and Earlier</title>

	<para>TODO- introduction</para>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm2003_install">
		<title>Installation</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm2003_configuration">
		<title>Configuration</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm2003_usage">
		<title>Usage</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id="synce_wm2003_troubleshooting">
		<title>Troubleshooting</title>

		<para>TODO</para>
	</sect1>

</chapter>

<chapter id="faq">
	<title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>

	<para>TODO</para>
</chapter>

</book>
